# **Kevin Alford**

138 S B St. Apt 1 San Mateo, CA 94401

kevin.alford@pixelflow.org 904.270.9376

Projects <a href="http://github.com/zeroeth">http://github.com/zeroeth</a> and <a href="http://codepen.io/zeroeth">http://github.com/zeroeth</a> and <a href="http://codepen.io/zeroeth">http://codepen.io/zeroeth</a> Blog <a href="http://blog.pixelflow.org">http://blog.pixelflow.org</a>

#### Skills

Languages: Ruby, Javascript, C++, Python, Java, Php, ObjectiveC, C#

Web Development

6 years Ruby on Rails experience, RESTful web applications and services.

Node.js/Express and PHP RESTful web applications and services.

Unobtrusive, accessible and degrading interfaces.

Semantic HTML and CSS using modern layout frameworks.

SVG and Canvas interactive graphics.

Mobile

iOS GPS based game engine, Cordova Android web app with native API calls.

Javascript

Single page applications with Backbone.js, 2D Games, 3D Art.

C#

UI, Networking, and Games in Unity3D.

Ruby

Desktop applications, command line, GUI, 2D and 3D OpenGL graphics.

Game programming, simulations, and Al.

Database

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and ORMs ActiveRecord, DataMapper, RedBean.

Testing

TDD in Ruby, Javascript, and C with a mixture of unit and integration tests.

Dev-Ops

Bash scripting, Puppet server deployment, Travis testing, Vagrant local development images.

Teamwork

Pair programming, Agile development using Pivotal, and Git.

### **Education**

Florida State College at Jacksonville: Programming AS, General AA. 3.6 gpa 2005-2008

#### **Interests**

Animatronics, puppetry, teaching, game programming, amateur radio, generative music, designing clocks, fractal world generation, photography, and trying new programming languages.

## **Personal Projects**

Arduino LED Goggles http://zeroeth.github.io/oculus\_aethereum

Unity3D Gravity Escape game <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/Gravity-Escape">https://github.com/zeroeth/Gravity-Escape</a>

Realistic "Hello World" examples <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/rosey">https://github.com/zeroeth/rosey</a>

Minecraft+JRuby maze generation <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/maze\_dungeon">https://github.com/zeroeth/maze\_dungeon</a>

Image color reduction art <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/shiver-me-dithers">https://github.com/zeroeth/shiver-me-dithers</a>

WebGL clock <a href="http://codepen.io/zeroeth/full/BGmHk">http://codepen.io/zeroeth/full/BGmHk</a>

Node.js brainwave recorder <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/brain.json">https://github.com/zeroeth/brain.json</a>

Ruby Magic card stats: https://github.com/zeroeth/daerb

Ruby Asteroids game <a href="http://github.com/zeroeth/nfgrebvqf">http://github.com/zeroeth/nfgrebvqf</a>

C OpenGL art: <a href="https://github.com/zeroeth/baubles">https://github.com/zeroeth/baubles</a>

#### **Employment**

Field Day Lab @ UW: UX/Software Engineer. 2013-2015

- Siftr.org Social photography app for promoting discussions around UW innovation and culture, using responsive CSS for mobile/tablet/desktop layouts.
- ARIS Location based games using an iOS app, php back-end, and javascript web application editor.

Software Assurance Marketplace: UX/Software Engineer. 2014

• **SWAMP** Web application for assisting developers in uncovering vulnerabilities by running static and dynamic analysis tools against their software.

Dock Technologies: UX/Software Engineer. 2013

Checkmate Patient information assistant for Nurses, using phonegap mobile framework

UW Madison Education Outreach Program: Teacher. 2012-2014

- Web Design Class Teaching kids modern CSS/HTML5/Grids/Typography/Color.
- Interactive Media & Electronics Class Teaching kids how to create reactive electronics and computer graphics with Arduino circuits and Processing code.
- Game Programming Class Teaching kids how to make 2d games in their web browser.

UW Madison / Games+Learning+Society: Software Engineer. 2011-2013

- Ada Single sign on for students, video game data collection, research and visualization.
- StudioK Web curriculum for teaching kids game design with Microsoft's Kodu.
- o **TrailsForward** Ecological simulation with tree growth and animal behavior.
- Magenta Network event publish/subscribe library for C# games written in Unity3D

Alorus: Ruby on Rails Web Developer. 2011

- **MediaMath Dashboard** Realtime situation display for at-a-glance trends in data being collected.
- Spreebird Daily Deals Deal aggregator site, using Paypal, RSS deal feed importing, and geographic searching.
- CBI Project management, ticketing and work-flow application with human language date parser.
- PeerVyne Social website where people subscribe to 'vynes' and post audio/video content.

Bear Den Designs: Ruby on Rails Web Developer, A/V engineer. 2007-2011

- Lutheran Medical Center Department of Dental Medicine "Outcomes" Portal for postdoc dentists to survey and report patient operations performed.
- ExperienceJax Events calendar with customizable repeating events, public moderation, and RSS feeds for specific areas of town, or categories.
- Kuotz Contractor centric bidding site where customers post jobs. features location based searching, online payment processing, and business verification check api.

Proximi: Ruby on Rails Web Developer. 2009

 AppAdvice iPhone app showcase site, created to suggest and review lists of similar applications with REST api access for mobile apps.

Alford Engineering: Audio Engineer. 2003-2013

Jacksonville Symphony Orchestra Recording for archival and radio broadcast.

Florida State College at Jacksonville Baymeadows: Java Web Developer. 2007

- Converted a paper student questionnaire into a web application.
- Access code generator for college textbooks.

Brooks Rehabilitation: Computer Technician. 2007

Sally Industries: Animatronics Animator/Programmer. 2005-2006

- Reese's Xtreme Cup Challenge Animate animatronic surfer sports announcers.
- Great Wolf Lodge in Niagara Falls Animate musical animal kids show.

Florida State College at Jacksonville Southside: Computer Technician. 2005

Providence School: Computer Technician. 2004-2005